All it brings in this video, we're going to have a look at the set interface and its subclasses.
So first things first, when are you going to use sets now when storing duplicate values is a concern.
That is you do not want duplicate values to be stored.
That's the first criteria for you to decide on what you want to use sets and their subclasses.
And obviously you're not going to use the set interface directly, you're going to use any of its subclasses.
In this video, we're going to have a look at two of those classes that is has set and entry set.
So starting with the has set class, I quickly go into the collections package again, new Java class and let's just call it working with has set.
And let's again have the mean method.
And now what I do is I just have a has set.
Again, as you're seeing from Java to detail, let's just make it with this timer integer only set.
Let's say we want to store IDs, right.
I'll just call it IDs of learners.
That's what we want to store.
Let's say new has set time at syntax.
We're good to go.
This is an integer only set now would not allow duplicates to be stored.
That's the first thing we're looking at sets.
And what brings us to has set, you will know by the end of this video.
So then next let's say set dot add, sorry, we've called it IDs of learners dot add again and interest rates integers.
This copy pasted a few times that we have some data to play around with.
And let's just say 345 1 0 3 2.
Some more numbers.
All right.
So now if you just sound and if you try to print this and say IDs of learners, okay, this would just print it out.
What is in the set.
So you would see that this just stores elements in what order.
Remember the analyst it was in search order with linked list.
It was in search order by index because we could add in between at the start and the add the end as well.
But with a has set you will see it is an unordered unsorted collection in Java.
It's only one of those two classes which are unordered as well as unsorted.
There would be no order that is guaranteed.
You're inserting in 345.
That's the first element.
And the last being 34.
But what you will get is is not guaranteed.
You'll see that's like here.
I'll just go on around this quickly off you go.
It says one.
It looks like it has sorted it.
But let's see one 34, but then one 032, then three 45, six, six, six, seven and all your machines that can be something else.
So the order with the last set is not guaranteed.
Right.
So that is unordered unsorted.
And let's say you try to duplicate values.
IDs of learners dot error gain.
Let's say I had a number which already exists.
I'll say one 032.
This would not be added, but it would not be an error.
I'll say no error, but wouldn't be right.
All right.
Let's have a look at this.
We'll just get it once.
And it says one 34, one 032 only once, three 45, six, six, six, seven and intelligence and tell it intelligent by its name.
You hover on the says that duplicate set element.
Right.
So no errors.
And it also gives you the return that has Boolean so that you can check it as I did in the last video with an if if this was added.
Let's say you're very quiet.
You want to do something.
If not added, you want to let's say print it out.
It was not added, but just doesn't doesn't work.
Otherwise, if you want to traverse it, go on and use the enhanced for loop or the for each whatever way you prefer.
So and and the other thing here is that is now what would what would how or when would you decide to use a high set.
The first thing is again, you want to, you want the duplicate values to not be stored.
All right.
That's the first requirement.
The second is has set.
When your requirement is you do not, you're not concerned with the order in which the elements would be stored.
You're not concerned in a for sorting.
So that is when you should decide using a has set.
It's an unordered and unsorted collection.